

OVERVIEW

Passionate javascript developer with 5+ years of experience, self-motivated, ambitious and eager to learn. a responsible individual with strong communication skills and work ethics besides being creative, focused and highly determined. At the same time, can work well in Team.

+971522200730 🕊

osamaalaa133@gmail.com 🔀

17 Al Drahi street , Abudhabi / UAE 💡

Osama Alaaeldin Senior Frontend Developer

SKILLS

HTML/CSS/Sass PHP Native/Codeigniter Three.is JavaScript/TypeScript React/Native/Redux OpenCV.js/Tensorflow.js D3.js/Chart.js Adobe Illustrator Next.is Firebase / AWS Cloud Vue.js/Require.js Docker Oracle (SQL/PL) Webpack Linux(Apache/Nginx) MYSQL Jquery/JQuery UI UnitTesting (Jasmine/Mocha.js) MongoDB Bootstrap 3 & 4 Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Yas Clinic Group, Abu Dhabi - UAE. Oct 2021 - Present

- Building reusable components using React.js Features
- . Translated Designs & wireframes into UI React Components via Typescript & javascript
- Responsible for creating efficient design and developingUser Interaction screens using HTML5, SASS, JavaScript, ¡Query, AJAX and JSON.
- . Built secure, scalable backend solutions and wrote Database queries and logic.
- Developed dynamic websites using PHP/MySQL
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

Senior Frontend Developer

CEPRES GMBH, Munich - Germany. Feb 2021 - Sep 2021

- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Using Typescript & Javascript for implementing the React components.
- Using Redux to perform state management.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.
- Documenting application changes and developing.

Senior React Developer

Aurora SDP, Ryadh Saud Arabia (Part time - remote). May 2021 - Oct 2021

- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts
- Using Javascript for implementing the React comps.
- Implementing server side rendering with Next.is.
- Implementing SEO concepts using Helmet && Next SEO.
- Using Redux to perform state management.
- Working in an agile team.

EDUCATION

AinShams University - Computer and Information Systems

Becholor of Computer Science / Scientific Computing 2014-2018

GP: AR For Kids using Computer Vision Technologies Grade: Excellent

AWARDS

Cloud Application Development in IBM July 2017

Mastery Award Badge UNIQUE ID: 6428-1499-9385-0286

Gold Badge Problem Solving in Hackerrank

Hackerrank: @osamaalaa133

Microsoft Azure Cloud in Microsoft Aug 2016

LINKS

- . github.com/osamaalaa
- . hackerrank.com/osamaalaa133
- . linkedin.com/in/osama-alaa/

Full-Stack developer (React - PHP)

Pharco Corporation, Alexandria - Egypt. Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

- Designed database schemas for ERPs systems through Oracle DB
- ntegrated oracle schemas with PHP codeigniter
- Using MVC design pattern to implement PHP APIs with

React components.

- Discussed projects progress with customers HRs and sales managers to collect feedback on direct stages and directly addresses concerns.
- Adding features for Procurement system and HR modules (ERP systems).
- Working in an agile team.

Backend developer (Nodejs)

Meits Technology Cairo , Egypt Sep 2018 - Jan 2020

- Developing and maintaining server-side network components.
- Ensuring optimal performance of the central database and responsiveness to front-end requests.
- Collaborating with front-end developers on the integration of elements.
- Designing customer-facing UI and back-end services for various business processes.
- Developing high-performance applications by writing testable, reusable, and efficient code.
- Implementing effective security protocols, data protection measures, and storage solutions.

Junior Frontend Developer

Foorera Cairo, Egypt June 2016 - June 2018 (Part time)

- Develop new user-facing features.
- Build reusable components for future use.
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.
- Optimize application for maximum speed and Scalability.
- Assure that all user input is validated before Submitting to back-end.
- Collaborate with other team members and Stakeholders

REFERENCES

Mr. Ahmed Amin

CEO Of Aurora SDP.

Call-+966 56 610 2757

Mr. Ramy Gomaa

CTO of Aurora SDP

Call-+20 100 199 5839

Ms . Christine Gürth

HR Manager of CEPRES GMBH Call-+49 89 23245605

Mr. Abdallah Emad

CTO Of Meits Techs

Call- +201068800085 **Mr. Mahmoud Eldes**

CTO Of Bookarage

Call-+966543203248

Languages

Arabic, English, Little German

HOBBES









